<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.3.3">Jekyll</generator><link href="/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2024-01-04T23:12:45+01:00</updated><id>/feed.xml</id><title type="html">Albert Azemar’s Blog</title><subtitle>My blog.</subtitle><entry><title type="html">So, the blog is back</title><link href="/so-the-blog-is-back/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="So, the blog is back" /><published>2023-01-04T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2023-01-04T00:00:00+01:00</updated><id>/so-the-blog-is-back</id><content type="html" xml:base="/so-the-blog-is-back/"><![CDATA[<p>So, the blog is back. If you are new here, let me introduce myself (not that I have an entire page devoted to myself here 😉). As you may have guessed, I’m called Albert Azemar i Rovira, and I’m the proud owner of this corner of the internet. This blog is, more or less, a little fun personal, and experimental project that I’ve been on and off since 2020. Now you’ll find a mashup of ideas, hobbies, experiences, reviews, and other content I feel might be insightful or that I enjoy writing about. But it wasn’t always like this. The blog is in its second (and hopefully final) reboot. As I said, albertazemar.com started amid the COVID-19 pandemic as a sort of Proof-of-Concept of the Django framework (the Python one), and it evolved into my personal blog. At that time, I did not post a lot, to be honest, and I soon received hefty AWS bills that I was not willing to pay. So, it went dark. I kept the domain just for the sake of it. Later, in 2022, I made the second attempt to stick to the habit (the inaugural post <a href="albertazemar.com/hello-world-again/">here</a>), but it also failed. I posted more content than in the first wave, or so I remember, but I felt blogging was more of an obligation rather than an activity I enjoyed.</p>

<p>After almost a year and a half after I published the last article titled “Name” my blog is back. Not only with new content, but the website has gotten a glow-up with a new look and feel. The new template has a more classy design and novel features that I will explore in the future. For the time being, I’m keeping it simple. This is the third time I have tried to stick to this project and, as ABBA said in their 1974 hit “Waterloo”:</p>

<blockquote>
  <p>‘The history book on the shelf is always repeating itself. Waterloo, Waterloo, I was defeated, you won the war’</p>
</blockquote>

<p>Let’s hope I succeed this time. But disco hits aside, yes, I’m back at the blogging gig. Not that I plan to make a living out of it, but for fun. This time, just for fun. Other attempts to keep a consistent stream of content flowing to this page were frustrated by the obligation I put to myself to blog about particular topics. This time it’s different. It will not have any directions or strings attached. The idea is to pour here whatever I feel like mixing at any given moment. The only rule is to post once a week, 52 posts this year. This is my pledge for 2024. It might seem a bit ambitious, but I have been optimizing the post-supply chain and focussing on how I can engage with this hobby constructively and positively.</p>

<h1 id="what-to-expect-in-this-new-chapter">What to expect in this new chapter</h1>

<p>So, 52 posts, what can you expect from that? I really don’t know. The cornerstones of my writing have been (and will be) my passions, hobbies, and experiences. This year, I’m picking up reading more seriously, and  I plan to review the books I go through. Moreover, I’ll be reading mostly nonfiction self-development, self-help, productivity, and economy/financial-related books. The idea is to extract actionable advice from each one (if it can be), post it alongside the review, and make myself accountable via this blog to take action. Much like Matt d’Avella does with his extraordinary series “I tried XYZ for 30 days”, I will also post about the little changes and experiments I conduct related to the action plans I make, the results I get, and the conclusions I extract.</p>

<p>Aside from that, the opera examinations will come back, as well as reviews about tools and objects that I enjoy and give value to my life. For example, I have been using the same Parker Jotter pen for the past seven almost eight years so I’m writing an in-depth review of this magnificent writing instrument that will be out soon.</p>

<p>Another format I want to explore is to review my record collection. I’ve been collecting vinyl for a substantial time now, and I feel like it’s time to share my passion for music through this format. This is more of a gray area of commitment since I literally don’t know where to start with this subject, but I’ll figure it out along the way.</p>

<p>Finally, this time also, I want to break the barrier of only posting “intellectual” content. During 2023 and 2024, I started to take care of my body. I began to go to the gym 5 times a week (3-4 times in practice) and noticed substantial changes and progress. And during the ski season, I plan to go to the mountains every weekend. This shift of perspective to care about my physical health has also been insightful and transformative, so I’ll post about this journey.</p>

<h1 id="what-about-the-old-content">What about the old content</h1>

<p>All the posts from version 2 of the blog are already posted and time-stamped with their original release date. I will add a disclaimer like <a href="https://www.tomscott.com">Tom Scott</a> does as a cringe/outdated content warning to ensure no one gets mad or confused. Regarding version 1 posts and the famous Moleskine open letter, I’ll try to recover them and repost them as an archive.</p>

<p>Features like the gallery, the song of the day, or the analog watch I’ll try to bring them back. But as I said, I’m focussing on enjoying so, no deadlines on that.</p>

<h1 id="next-steps">Next steps</h1>

<p>I would say, sit back, relax, and expect an annoying WhatsApp message from me every time I post (I’m assuming that I know all my readers, and I’m probably right). I quit Instagram many moons ago, and I won’t go back to promote this blog, so if you are not on my texting list, I’m planning on setting up a mailing list to notify you whenever new posts go live and an RSS feed (more on this in a future post). But for the time being, F5 is your best friend.</p>

<p>Best wishes for 2024, and I hope you also achieve all your goals!</p>]]></content><author><name>albert752</name></author><category term="personal" /><category term="featured" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[So, the blog is back. If you are new here, let me introduce myself (not that I have an entire page devoted to myself here 😉). As you may have guessed, I’m called Albert Azemar i Rovira, and I’m the proud owner of this corner of the internet. This blog is, more or less, a little fun personal, and experimental project that I’ve been on and off since 2020. Now you’ll find a mashup of ideas, hobbies, experiences, reviews, and other content I feel might be insightful or that I enjoy writing about. But it wasn’t always like this. The blog is in its second (and hopefully final) reboot. As I said, albertazemar.com started amid the COVID-19 pandemic as a sort of Proof-of-Concept of the Django framework (the Python one), and it evolved into my personal blog. At that time, I did not post a lot, to be honest, and I soon received hefty AWS bills that I was not willing to pay. So, it went dark. I kept the domain just for the sake of it. Later, in 2022, I made the second attempt to stick to the habit (the inaugural post here), but it also failed. I posted more content than in the first wave, or so I remember, but I felt blogging was more of an obligation rather than an activity I enjoyed.]]></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="/2023-01-04-so-the-blog-is-back/IMG_0997.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="/2023-01-04-so-the-blog-is-back/IMG_0997.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Magic the Gathering, Dreams and Nostalgia</title><link href="/mtg-dreams-and-nostalgia-copy/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Magic the Gathering, Dreams and Nostalgia" /><published>2022-08-09T00:00:00+02:00</published><updated>2022-08-09T00:00:00+02:00</updated><id>/mtg-dreams-and-nostalgia%20copy</id><content type="html" xml:base="/mtg-dreams-and-nostalgia-copy/"><![CDATA[<p>People that have known me since I was an undergrad know that from 2015 to 2019, I was an active Magic The Gathering (MTG) player. For the uninitiated, MTG is a trading card game invented by Richard Garfield in the 90s. Each player must build a deck with a minimum of 60 cards with a maximum of 4 copies of the same card. These can be chosen from a pool of thousands. Then, you level yourself against an opponent to the best of three. Each week, I would take part in the Friday Night Magic (FNM) tournaments of my local games store. I never became a master or anything close, but I loved playing the game. My peak performance was achieving 16th place in a national pauper event with a meme deck. In any case, I met some tremendous people there, and the game made me escape reality for a couple of hours.</p>

<p>That was until I stopped. To be honest, I don’t know why I did. Maybe because my degree getting harder? Or because my life was turned upside down on 2019, and MTG didn’t fit anymore? I honestly don’t know. Yesterday though, I had a dream where I was playing a game. The last memories I have of the Magic are in the online MTG Arena platform with someone who used to be one of my best friends. It wasn’t the same as tabletop magic, but it worked particularly well as a replacement to quench your thirst.</p>

<p>I felt some much joy and happiness during the dream that I decided to install it once to see if I could recreate the feelings I experienced. As I was waiting for it to completely download, I navigated to <a href="https://www.mtggoldfish.com">MTGGoldfish</a>, a website I used to visit to check decks and articles about the game. Much to my surprise, my go-to deck was no longer in the Pauper metagame. A quick google search revealed that one of the winning strategies was cut off with some card bans. Furthermore, a bunch of new sets with bizarre new mechanics had been introduced since I last checked. I was overwhelmed and immediately begin to feel like a stranger reading about the game. Magic was an essential part of my life, and it was as if I didn’t know about the game at all. This was not a very pleasant feeling.</p>

<p>Things worsened when I fired up MTG Arena: all my old decks were not playable due to rotation. Furthermore, most of the interfaces and menus were new. Time waits for no one and it didn’t wait for me. It was clear that I no longer was knowledgeable in the subject. My next move was to net-deck an easy-to-play aggro deck that could suit my playing style, and I tried to get started again. It only got worst. As I mentioned, I never was very talented at it, but I knew my way around beginners. I did lose every game. This left me with a bitter taste and prompted me to write this article.</p>

<p>During this painful process, some sweet memories of those years as a player come back to my mind. It was my Friday routine: go to the store, buy some cards I needed for a deck I was building and pay three euros to play. I usually end up in the middle of the standings, rarely earning any money. I attribute this lack of success to my level of maturity. But I digress, afterwards I would have a long talk with a dear friend of mine that was also a player. Once we said our goodbyes, he would take a rental bike home while I was greeted back home with a pizza. I would then try to create a new deck with a novel strategy until my eyelids felt too heavy and I fell asleep. I remember I used to play on <a href="https://cockatrice.github.io">Cockatrice</a>, a not official MTG platform. Maybe I will go back to the old formats I know better and play there. I sure hope to write more about my journey with MTG.</p>

<p>Anyways, for all I know, those times are long gone. Personal and professional progress has been made since then. Nevertheless, I can’t help feeling a bit nostalgic about those “good old days”, and reflect on the lessons I’ve learned since then.</p>]]></content><author><name>albert752</name></author><category term="personal" /><category term="spotlight" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[People that have known me since I was an undergrad know that from 2015 to 2019, I was an active Magic The Gathering (MTG) player. For the uninitiated, MTG is a trading card game invented by Richard Garfield in the 90s. Each player must build a deck with a minimum of 60 cards with a maximum of 4 copies of the same card. These can be chosen from a pool of thousands. Then, you level yourself against an opponent to the best of three. Each week, I would take part in the Friday Night Magic (FNM) tournaments of my local games store. I never became a master or anything close, but I loved playing the game. My peak performance was achieving 16th place in a national pauper event with a meme deck. In any case, I met some tremendous people there, and the game made me escape reality for a couple of hours.]]></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="/2022-08-09-mtg-dreams-and-nostalgia/41mztsnrdm.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="/2022-08-09-mtg-dreams-and-nostalgia/41mztsnrdm.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Francis Albert Sinatra, My Way and all that jazz</title><link href="/francis-albert-sinatra-my-way-and-all-that-jazz/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Francis Albert Sinatra, My Way and all that jazz" /><published>2022-05-17T00:00:00+02:00</published><updated>2022-05-17T00:00:00+02:00</updated><id>/francis-albert-sinatra-my-way-and-all-that-jazz</id><content type="html" xml:base="/francis-albert-sinatra-my-way-and-all-that-jazz/"><![CDATA[<p>Francis Albert Sinatra or as commonly known as Frank Sinatra is, in my humble opinion, one of the best crooners that ever lived. His songs have healed my soul when I needed it the most, guided me while dealing with my feelings, and empowered me to make bold decisions in my life. Even though we never shared a time frame in our existence, I have to thank him for always being there for me.</p>

<p>It was during the summer of 2019 that a dear friend of mine introduced me to Jazz. I already knew who Frank was. Who doesn’t? I usually listened to some of his most beloved songs before. It wasn’t until I dived into the intricate Jazz rabbit hole that I could appreciate the magic of his repertoire. The lyrics of his songs healed me, gave me hope for a brighter future, and by all means, made a significant impact on the person that I’ve become since then.</p>

<p>I’m fully aware that most of his tunes were not written by him and, My Way, my personal favorite, is one of them. Despite, you have to admit that sometimes the delivery of the message is as important as the message itself. Here is where Sinatra excels. His deep and rich voice reaches your soul and makes you feel every phrase of the lyrics. I felt so in love with My Way that I have these exact words tattoed on my forearm. For me is an anthem of independence and self-liberation. A song that speaks of taking matters into your own hands, listening to your inner self, and acting accordingly. In this life, you can lie to anyone but yourself.</p>

<p>But My Way is not the end of this love story: Summer Wind, Come Fly With Me, The Best Is Yet To Come, Luck Be A Lady, Fly Me To The Moon, The Good Live, to name a few. And I could go on for a quite long list. There is something special in each of his songs that makes them little pieces of sweet candy for your delight.</p>

<p>I will never get tired of him. Despite not listening to his records as often as I used to, they will always be there. When you need them the most, they will provide a comfortable atmosphere to ponder, relax and introspect.</p>

<p>Thank you from the bottom of my heart.</p>]]></content><author><name>albert752</name></author><category term="personal" /><category term="spotlight" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Francis Albert Sinatra or as commonly known as Frank Sinatra is, in my humble opinion, one of the best crooners that ever lived. His songs have healed my soul when I needed it the most, guided me while dealing with my feelings, and empowered me to make bold decisions in my life. Even though we never shared a time frame in our existence, I have to thank him for always being there for me.]]></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="/2022-05-17-francis-albert-sinatra-my-way-and-all-that-jazz/cover.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="/2022-05-17-francis-albert-sinatra-my-way-and-all-that-jazz/cover.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">A Night at the Opera: Così Fan Tutte</title><link href="/a-night-at-the-opera-cosi-fan-tutte/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="A Night at the Opera: Così Fan Tutte" /><published>2022-04-22T00:00:00+02:00</published><updated>2022-04-22T00:00:00+02:00</updated><id>/a-night-at-the-opera-cosi-fan-tutte</id><content type="html" xml:base="/a-night-at-the-opera-cosi-fan-tutte/"><![CDATA[<p>I’ve just arrived home from the Gran Teatre del Liceu. Tonight I witnessed one of the most magical opera nights of my life. The play was Cosi Fan Tutte, the third collaboration between Wolfgang Amadeus Mozart and Lorenzo da Ponte. Let me tell you that I’m still in shock. The amount of joy, laughter, and overall positive feelings that I’ve experienced tonight was unprecedented.</p>

<p>As per usual, I arrived 20 minutes before the start. I located my seats on the main floor, row 6, seat number 2. I couldn’t have chosen a better location. As it has been a running theme during the Mozart - da Ponte trilogy, instead of having the curtain down, the stage manager decided to leave them up. You can see the actors and actresses stretching, enjoying a casual conversation, and getting ready for the show. At 19h the performance began. A well-suited man promptly interrupted the action to make an announcement. Both sopranos portraying Fiordiligi and Dorabella had tested positive for COVID19. Also, the baritone who plays the role of Guglielmo suffered an injury and was left out of the cast. But the oddest announcement was that the role of Dorabella was to be played by Arianna Vendittelli in the vocal part and by Anna Ponces in the acting part. As you might guess, this was not going to be your usual night at the opera.</p>

<p>The action starts, and the music fills all the corners of the room. I knew some of the pieces I was going to enjoy. As always, live music never disappoints. We then reach the point when Don Alfonso tells Dorabella and Fiordiligi that their fiancés have been called to go to war. Fiordiligi faints. After your usual 5 seconds of opera drama, I started to wonder: why isn’t the actress standing up? And my suspicions that something was wrong were confirmed when the whole cast started shouting in their native languages: No! no!. My first instinct was that someone had screwed up. As if the actress didn’t have to faint or she was singing the wrong lines. Don Alfonso, portrayed by Alexandre Duhamel, interpellates the public and asks: Is there a doctor? At this point, you could see that something was off, as the levels of concern of the cast were not indicating real danger. He proceeds by saying: Oh I’ve got it! And goes to pick up a nostril swab, like the ones used in COVID tests, walks towards Iulia Maria Dan (the actress that portrays Fiordiligi), and shouts in Italian: A PCR TEST! The crowd cracks up laughing as he fakes the testing procedure, and the poor Fiordiligi wakes up. You could say that it was just a joke. But for me, it had a bit more depth. The whole approach to the trilogy has been based on the roots of the opera, on the street theater, the <em>opera bufa</em>. The kind of acting that you could enjoy on the streets, that made fun of the mundane. That is why the curtain was left open, for example. So, even if it was not intentional, I found it to be more clever than it seemed and perfectly blended with the approach that the Liceu took for the opera.</p>

<p>The rest of the opera developed marvelously. I truly fell in love with the voices of both sopranos: Arianna Vendittelli and Iulia Maria Dan. I laughed and felt joy with the fantastic interpretation of Despina by Miriam Albano. Concerning the male voices, I had seen Alexandre Duhamel as Don Giovani the week before. He has an incredible voice and a magnificent way to make you smile, even when you are not supposed to. Finally, the interpretation of the last two male characters: Ferrando and Guglielmo portrayed by James Ley and Florian Sempey was outstanding. You could say at some point that it was a group of friends on a night out at the karaoke.</p>

<p>The opera ended, and I still had a hunger for more. I can’t stress enough the positive emotions I felt with the interpretations of Arianna Vendittelli and Iulia Maria Dan. But the cherry on top had still to arrive. As the tradition goes, the conductor joins the cast for the final salute. All of a sudden, he stops the clapping to make an announcement. First of all, he congratulates the orchestra for an amazing performance. And then he congratulates both the sopranos for pulling off an amazing interpretation given that it was the first time they did the whole thing together. I was stonished. That cast, all together, with the orchestra, had never played the entire thing before? I mean, if this is not the works of some kind of bizarre magic, I don’t know what it is.</p>

<p>Finally, as the emotions wear off, I want to tackle the moral of the story. In this instance it could be summed up as: humans can’t be 100% faithful. And, by assuming that, we can not live trying to test our significant others because they will eventually fall into the temptation as Dorabell and Fiordiligi do. This conclusion has aged quite well. Nowadays, we see how toxic controlling relationships collapse with disastrous consequences. We could all take a page from Cosi Fan Tuttes’ <em>libretto</em>. I won’t elaborate much about this topic. I’m just pointing it out as something to think about and meditate on.</p>

<p>If you haven’t seen Così Fan Tutte, I highly recommend it. If you can’t, you can still grasp a bit of information by listening to <em>La previa del Liceu</em>. A podcast, both in Catalan and Spanish, that gives the audience the required background information to truly enjoy the play. Being usually considered the underdog of the trilogy, I had lower expectations. But, in my opinion, it deserves to be considered at the same level as its cousins: Le Nozze di Figaro and Don Giovani. I’m sure it won’t disappoint you.</p>]]></content><author><name>albert752</name></author><category term="opera" /><category term="spotlight" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[I’ve just arrived home from the Gran Teatre del Liceu. Tonight I witnessed one of the most magical opera nights of my life. The play was Cosi Fan Tutte, the third collaboration between Wolfgang Amadeus Mozart and Lorenzo da Ponte. Let me tell you that I’m still in shock. The amount of joy, laughter, and overall positive feelings that I’ve experienced tonight was unprecedented.]]></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="/2022-04-22-a-night-at-the-opera-cosi-fan-tutte/cosi-fan-tutte.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="/2022-04-22-a-night-at-the-opera-cosi-fan-tutte/cosi-fan-tutte.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">New Feature: Gallery</title><link href="/new-feature-gallery/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="New Feature: Gallery" /><published>2022-04-20T00:00:00+02:00</published><updated>2022-04-20T00:00:00+02:00</updated><id>/new-feature-gallery</id><content type="html" xml:base="/new-feature-gallery/"><![CDATA[<p>I’m quitting Instagram. I’m sick and tired of wasting my precious time scrolling. I always thought of myself as someone above all of those issues that are often pointed out about social media. But the situation has reached a point where I can’t take it anymore. The amount of hours that I’m pouring on the platform is increasing exponentially, so I quit.</p>

<p>I haven’t talked about it yet, but I’m into analog photography. Instagram served as an outlet to display my pictures. Since I’m abandoning the platform for good, I’ll share my journey here on my blog. I’ve created a section called <a href="https://albertazemar.com/gallery">Gallery</a>. There you’ll find a selection of my favorite pictures. I’ll be updating it as I develop more film rolls. I’m still not sure if I like the current format. I’m using <a href="https://github.com/mfg92">mfg92</a> shortcode to create the gallery called hugo-shortcode-gallery. You can find it <a href="https://github.com/mfg92/hugo-shortcode-gallery">here</a>.</p>

<p>The image I selected as the cover for this post was taken in Sitges. It illustrates the beauty of analog photography. It might seem that it has been composed with some kind of computer software. But no, it’s an anomaly, an error. This image is a double exposure with a peculiar filter in the middle created by the roll. A phenomenon that Bob Ross would define as a happy accident. I find in these exceptions the beauty of the format. The uncertainty, expectation, and thrill that you feel when you receive your developed rolls can’t be matched by the digital world.</p>

<p>This weekend, a friend of mine gave me a quick masterclass on manual photography. I use a restored Canon AE-1 Program. Its main feature is the automatic mode that turns your DSLR into a point-and-shoot. I had no prior experience in photography so I’d been using it since I bought the camera. I’m now trying to use the manual mode to experience even more the creative side of analog photography. I’ll be documenting my experience and my learning process in manual mode here on my blog.</p>

<p>In the meantime, enjoy the new feature. I hope you have a wonderful end of the week!</p>]]></content><author><name>albert752</name></author><category term="analog photography" /><category term="announcement" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[I’m quitting Instagram. I’m sick and tired of wasting my precious time scrolling. I always thought of myself as someone above all of those issues that are often pointed out about social media. But the situation has reached a point where I can’t take it anymore. The amount of hours that I’m pouring on the platform is increasing exponentially, so I quit.]]></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="/2022-04-20-new-feature-gallery/Photo12_12.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="/2022-04-20-new-feature-gallery/Photo12_12.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Planes Busses and Opera</title><link href="/planes-busses-and-opera/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Planes Busses and Opera" /><published>2022-04-16T00:00:00+02:00</published><updated>2022-04-16T00:00:00+02:00</updated><id>/planes-busses-and-opera</id><content type="html" xml:base="/planes-busses-and-opera/"><![CDATA[<p>Planes, busses, and opera
Well, I’ve just landed at Bilbao Airport. I’m having a bit of a headache, probably caused by sleep deprivation or caffeine withdrawal. So ordering a double expresso seemed to be the obvious solution. Little did I know that I would be greeted with an overpriced coffee soup worthy to be served at Central Perk.</p>

<p>To reach my final destination, Zarautz, I’m taking a bus that leaves in 30 minutes. So, I have some time to spear. And nothing better to do than to break the configuration of the URxvt terminal emulator on my netbook. I said to myself: the font is not big enough, let’s fix that! And now it is not running anymore. As they say, a problem for the future me. This PC is not my daily driver. I bought it years ago when I was at university. It has served me well with its top-tier specs including a whopping 2Gb of ram. So TLDR, I’m typing on my phone. This will be a fun one to spellcheck.</p>

<p>The bus trip should last no more than an hour. I’m tired but the caffeine, or at least the placebo effect, is starting to kick in. It’s a cloudy day in Bilbao. A thick fog covers pretty much everything. I’m listening to my opera and classical music playlist. I often find myself enjoying my favorite operas in times of solitude. It’s weird but it fills my heart with joy.</p>

<p>I’m a fan of the genre. In 2019, my best friend found out that our local opera house, el Gran Teatre del Liceu, offered discounts for those of us under 35 years old. Two weeks before the premiere, all the unsold tickets are offered for just 30€. And that’s not all, guess what kind of tickets are usually left unsold: the most expensive ones. So we always find ourselves in the most luxurious boxes or on the main floor. We have kept this tradition ever since, only to be broken by covid. Every month there is a new opera to enjoy. The list of shows I’ve seen so far goes, in strict chronological order:</p>

<ul>
  <li>La Traviata</li>
  <li>Turandot</li>
  <li>Doña Francisquita</li>
  <li>Cavalleria Rusticana / Pagliacci</li>
  <li>Aida</li>
  <li>Ariadne Auf Naxos</li>
  <li>Rigoletto</li>
  <li>Píkovaia dama</li>
  <li>Pelleas et Melisandre</li>
  <li>Le Nozze de Figaró</li>
  <li>Don Giovanni</li>
  <li>Cosi fan Tutte (I’ll go next week)</li>
</ul>

<p>I’m planning on writing a review for each one and to extract a ranking out of it. I’m not an expert by any means, I just want to share my experience. Also, I’m interested to dive deeper into this world and expanding my knowledge.</p>

<p>One other thing I want to point out about going to the opera is the difficulties to find someone to go with. As I said, I usually go with a friend of mine. But he does not live in Barcelona so logistics get difficult from time to time. Because of that, I sometimes end up having to go alone. At first, I did not like the idea. I don’t usually enjoy being around crowds alone. But as I faced the “challenge” more and more, I found that you can be your best company. I mean, don’t get me wrong, I love going with my friend, but going alone it’s a different experience. It lets you be more present and with yourself. I don’t know, classical music affects my mood. It relaxes me, makes me shift down gears, and makes me more present.</p>

<p>Well, it seems that I have derailed enough for today. I don’t know how, when, and if I’m going to publish the whole thing or not. We’ll see. Have a wonderful Easter holiday and enjoy the well-deserved (or not) vacations.</p>]]></content><author><name>albert752</name></author><category term="personal" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Planes, busses, and opera Well, I’ve just landed at Bilbao Airport. I’m having a bit of a headache, probably caused by sleep deprivation or caffeine withdrawal. So ordering a double expresso seemed to be the obvious solution. Little did I know that I would be greeted with an overpriced coffee soup worthy to be served at Central Perk.]]></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="/2022-04-16-planes-busses-and-opera/cover.jpeg" /><media:content medium="image" url="/2022-04-16-planes-busses-and-opera/cover.jpeg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Catalan Chess League 2022 Round 3: My First Classical Game</title><link href="/catalan-chess-league-round-3/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Catalan Chess League 2022 Round 3: My First Classical Game" /><published>2022-04-14T00:00:00+02:00</published><updated>2022-04-14T00:00:00+02:00</updated><id>/catalan-chess-league-round-3</id><content type="html" xml:base="/catalan-chess-league-round-3/"><![CDATA[<p>Well after I started taking chess lessons, I received an unexpected e-mail: I was selected to play in the Catalan chess league next Sunday. Being a Tuesday, I was at the office. And having started in a new company merely two weeks ago, I was not in shape. I had neglected chess training for most of that month. In all that mess, I forgot to uncheck my name from the available player’s list for that game.</p>

<p>Not only I had speedrun my training, but I was also playing with black. All my prep was around d4 openings with white so go figure how did I feel. I talked to my manager and kindly asked him if he would let me work from home for the rest of the week so I could save up the 1h20 commute. He agreed. Thus began my epic training montage, like in karate kid. My prep was centered on e4 openings and not by employing a swiss army knife like the King’s Indian.</p>

<p>The day arrived. I woke up, took a shower, drank my coffee, ate something to avoid starvation, and headed to the metro. I was nervous, very nervous, almost shaking. I arrived there just to find out that the boards did not have guides. So I had to rely on myself for notation, great, another bump down the road. I looked for my board, sat down, put on my trusted earplugs and this was it, game on!</p>

<h1 id="game-analysis">Game analysis</h1>
<p>So the game began on time. The first moves were your usual scotch opening. Fun fact, the Friday before this game, my trainer asked me what did I want to review. I suggested taking a look at the most common variations of the scotch.</p>

<blockquote>
  <ol>
    <li>e4 e5 2. Nf3 Nc6 3. d4 exd4 4. Nxd4 Bc5</li>
  </ol>
</blockquote>

<p>So we arrive at this common position in the scotch:</p>

<figure class="uk-margin-medium">
    <img src="/uploads/2022-04-14-catalan-chess-league-round-3/diagram00.svg" alt="White to play" />
    
</figure>

<p>My prep at this point was 5. Be3 or 5. Nxc6, but his move was</p>

<blockquote>
  <ol>
    <li>Nf5</li>
  </ol>
</blockquote>

<p>So as a first-timer in classical over-the-board chess, I learned my first lesson: prep can’t get you as far as you would always wish. Note that Nf5 is indeed a sideline but not one I had prepared. So I started to think. By applying the principles of chess, I came up with the next move:</p>

<blockquote>
  <ol>
    <li>.. Qf6</li>
  </ol>
</blockquote>

<p>So what were my thoughts behind this? Well, two. First of all, it develops a piece that is what you are always told to do during the opening. But secondly, it pins the knight. Any move of this piece (except for Kxg7, which would hang the unit) hangs mate in 1 by Qxf2#.</p>

<p>After analyzing this game with my coach, I found out that the mainline in that position was not Qf6. The best move was d5. I can’t say that I saw it. I was a bit afraid of all the lines in which I had to sacrifice the g2 pawn and move the king.</p>

<p>So well, now it was time for my opponent to make a move, and oh boy did this next move puzzled me:</p>

<blockquote>
  <ol>
    <li>h4?</li>
  </ol>
</blockquote>

<p>It appears to be a very questionable move. As if my opponent was trying to set up an attack on the kings’ side. I didn’t understand the meaning of it. But, despite being freakishly nervous, I started to think. Again, by carefully applying the principles of the game, I followed the logic:  the knight on f5 is his most active piece and, since we are in the opening, we have to develop. Oh, I see! He is not developing his pieces. Let’s exploit that. How?</p>

<blockquote>
  <ol>
    <li>.. Nge7</li>
  </ol>
</blockquote>

<p>If he trades? I’m happy, I’ll castle and we live to fight for another day. If he retreats? Happy as well. I’m making him lose a tempo. But none of those things happened. He played with a concept that Levy Rozman (GothamChess) usually talks about, danger levels. Wich means generating a higher threat to force your opponent to respond. And the move was:</p>

<blockquote>
  <ol>
    <li>Bg5??</li>
  </ol>
</blockquote>

<p>Again, I did not expect that. The first thing I saw was the hanging b2 pawn. Rather than rushing, I stepped back. I thought: this could be a trap. He’s trying to pull off an attack. Is he for real? Well, after some calculations, it turns out that he wasn’t. My next move was obvious, followed by an almost forced response.</p>

<blockquote>
  <p>Qxb2 8. Nd2</p>
</blockquote>

<p>Then, I stuck with my plan of punishing his underdevelopment and gently castled:</p>

<blockquote>
  <p>Nxf5 9. exf5 O-O</p>
</blockquote>

<p>I’m not going to lie. It was at this point where I thought: Albert, we might win this game. See it for yourself:</p>

<figure class="uk-margin-medium">
    <img src="/uploads/2022-04-14-catalan-chess-league-round-3/diagram01.svg" alt="White to play" />
    
</figure>

<p>Now his choices were few. He saw my queen infiltrating on the seventh. He tried to kick her out. An opportunity that I took to deliver a check and gobble two more other pawns. I was very proud of myself: despite being in a winning position, I was able to calculate all the possible responses to my check and each one of the consequences. I did not lose focus.</p>

<blockquote>
  <ol>
    <li>Rb1 Qe5+ 11. Qe2 Qxf5 12. g4 Qxc2 13. Rd1</li>
  </ol>
</blockquote>

<p>And we arrive at the following position:</p>

<figure class="uk-margin-medium">
    <img src="/uploads/2022-04-14-catalan-chess-league-round-3/diagram02.svg" alt="Black to play" />
    
</figure>

<p>With the white king surrounded by its pieces, the smell of the smothered mate was there. Also, you could see the alignment of the queen and the king on the e file. Very juicy for a pin. After several minutes of thinking, I decided to go with:</p>

<blockquote>
  <ol>
    <li>.. d6</li>
  </ol>
</blockquote>

<p>And the nerves and insecurities came crawling. My biggest flaw in chess is that I tend to step out of the gas pedal in winning positions. d6 seemed a slow move. The intentions were to exploit the fact that the queen was aligned with the king and to develop the light square bishop. From an objective point of view, it was a good move. But you know, my head was somewhere else. His response was as follows:</p>

<blockquote>
  <ol>
    <li>Rh3 Bd7 15. Qf3</li>
  </ol>
</blockquote>

<p>And at this point, my opponent went for a smoke. The obvious move was Rae8+, but again, being my first game I calculated, just in case an obscure line came up. Nevertheless, nothing worth taking into account emerged so I did play:</p>

<blockquote>
  <ol>
    <li>.. Rae8+</li>
  </ol>
</blockquote>

<p>He was looking at the board through a window. He came back and slammed the board with:</p>

<blockquote>
  <ol>
    <li>Be2 Nd4</li>
  </ol>
</blockquote>

<p>I was proud of uncorking that fork. Out of options, my opponent tried to create some chaos at my queens’ side without much result:</p>

<blockquote>
  <ol>
    <li>Qxb7 Nxe2</li>
  </ol>
</blockquote>

<p>And yes, Rxe2 was mate in 7, I think. But I was having a bit of tunnel vision, trying to deliver mate with the knight. Finally, we simplified the board with:</p>

<blockquote>
  <ol>
    <li>Be3 Nc3 19. Qb3 Qxb3 20. Nxb3 Nxd1 21. Nxc5 dxc5 22. Rg3</li>
  </ol>
</blockquote>

<p>And now, a question for you, the reader: Why didn’t he take the knight?</p>

<figure class="uk-margin-medium">
    <img src="/uploads/2022-04-14-catalan-chess-league-round-3/diagram03.svg" alt="White to play" />
    
</figure>

<p>Well because, after Kxd1, comes Bxg4, forking the king and the rook. I did see this trick and, let me say it, I was filled with joy. The game ended in the following way:</p>

<blockquote>
  <p>Nxe3 23. fxe3 Re4 24. Kd2 Rxg4 25. Rf3 Rxh4 26. Rf1 Rh2+ 27. Kd3 Bb5+ *</p>
</blockquote>

<p>He conceded after the skewer landed on the board. The final position was the following:</p>

<figure class="uk-margin-medium">
    <img src="/uploads/2022-04-14-catalan-chess-league-round-3/diagram04.svg" alt="White to play" />
    
</figure>

<h1 id="takeaways">Takeaways</h1>
<p>All in all, I’m delighted with the outcome. Despite my opponents’ mistakes, I still had to think and try to exploit the positions as much as I possibly could.</p>

<p>Looking back I did enjoy the experience but at the moment… I was extremely nervous. I can’t stress it enough. But that is something that I will have to figure out. Years ago, I used to play MTG (Magic the Gathering), and yes, I was as nervous as I could be during my firsts Friday Night Magic tournaments. But after some games, things became familiar and more enjoyable. I think that what I need is to expose myself to more OTB games and learn by experience how to calm down.</p>

<h1 id="catalan-federation-of-chess-elo">Catalan Federation of Chess ELO</h1>
<p>Since we are not playing in the first league, I’m only awarded Catalan ELO points. Your starting score is 1700. Since my opponent was 1649, I gained 17 ELO points. You can check out my progress <a href="https://escacs.cat/index.php/component/fce?op=13&amp;idJugador=397264&amp;nom=">here</a>.</p>]]></content><author><name>albert752</name></author><category term="chess" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Well after I started taking chess lessons, I received an unexpected e-mail: I was selected to play in the Catalan chess league next Sunday. Being a Tuesday, I was at the office. And having started in a new company merely two weeks ago, I was not in shape. I had neglected chess training for most of that month. In all that mess, I forgot to uncheck my name from the available player’s list for that game.]]></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="/2022-04-14-catalan-chess-league-round-3/mechess.jpeg" /><media:content medium="image" url="/2022-04-14-catalan-chess-league-round-3/mechess.jpeg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Hello World, Again!</title><link href="/hello-world-again/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Hello World, Again!" /><published>2022-04-11T00:00:00+02:00</published><updated>2022-04-11T00:00:00+02:00</updated><id>/hello-world-again</id><content type="html" xml:base="/hello-world-again/"><![CDATA[<p>So my blog is back. I started this project in March 2020 during the lockdown as a fun way to learn a bit about Django, python’s web app framework, and AWS (Amazon Web Services). I had some prior experience using Django from my first internship at NTT. If you are someone who has an interest in diving into this framework, I would strongly recommend CoreyMS <sup id="fnref:1" role="doc-noteref"><a href="#fn:1" class="footnote" rel="footnote">1</a></sup> video series on YouTube about it. It covers the basics needed, provided you have a good understanding of the python programming language.</p>

<p>Then, time went by and I left the project with only three posts (shame on me). Also, a year after, the AWS Free tier plan that I was using expired. So, after two painful +30€ bills, I decided to shut it down. I kept renewing the domain though just in case. Fun fact, I did use the running implementation of the old blog as the deliverable for a masters’ degree subject. In teams, we had to develop a web app with security by design. So not wanting to socialize with the rest of my mates (long story short, two of them are now coworkers of mine and we get along pretty well), I asked the professor if it would be ok to use my blog as the deliverable. She said no problem and hey, it was graded with the maximum score so, not bad at all.</p>

<p>Lately, I had been thinking about going back to writing a blog. I tried to self-host the old implementation, but it was pretty much outdated and needed to be rewritten. After not so careful consideration, I ended up choosing Hugo with GitHub hosting. I plan on migrating it to my home server but IT security is not as easy as it might seem.</p>

<p>So, now what? Well, my idea is to post daily but I find this goal a bit unreachable. So I’m willing to commit to at least one post per week. I have many ideas about subjects to cover and series of various topics to tackle but we’ll see. I don’t want this blog turning into a chore rather than a hobby so as Doris Day sang: Que sera, sera. Whatever will be, will be. So yes, now I can defently shout again to people: This is so going in my blog!</p>
<div class="footnotes" role="doc-endnotes">
  <ol>
    <li id="fn:1" role="doc-endnote">
      <p>Link to the course <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=UmljXZIypDc&amp;list=PL-osiE80TeTtoQCKZ03TU5fNfx2UY6U4p">here</a>. <a href="#fnref:1" class="reversefootnote" role="doc-backlink">&#8617;</a></p>
    </li>
  </ol>
</div>]]></content><author><name>albert752</name></author><category term="personal" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[So my blog is back. I started this project in March 2020 during the lockdown as a fun way to learn a bit about Django, python’s web app framework, and AWS (Amazon Web Services). I had some prior experience using Django from my first internship at NTT. If you are someone who has an interest in diving into this framework, I would strongly recommend CoreyMS 1 video series on YouTube about it. It covers the basics needed, provided you have a good understanding of the python programming language. Link to the course here. &#8617;]]></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="/2022-04-11-hello-world-again/01980028.JPG" /><media:content medium="image" url="/2022-04-11-hello-world-again/01980028.JPG" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry></feed>