<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"><channel><title>Albert Azemars' Blog</title><link>https://albertazemar.com/</link><description>Recent content on Albert Azemars' Blog</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 09 Aug 2022 00:14:16 +0200</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://albertazemar.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Magic the Gathering, Dreams and Nostalgia</title><link>https://albertazemar.com/posts/mtg-dreams-and-nostalgia/</link><pubDate>Tue, 09 Aug 2022 00:14:16 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://albertazemar.com/posts/mtg-dreams-and-nostalgia/</guid><description>People that have known me since I was an undergrad know that from 2015 to 2019, I was an active Magic The Gathering (MTG) player. For the uninitiated, MTG is a trading card game invented by Richard Garfield in the 90s. Each player must build a deck with a minimum of 60 cards with a maximum of 4 copies of the same card. These can be chosen from a pool of thousands.</description></item><item><title>Francis Albert Sinatra, My Way and all that jazz</title><link>https://albertazemar.com/posts/francis-albert-sinatra-my-way-and-all-that-jazz/</link><pubDate>Tue, 17 May 2022 23:12:03 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://albertazemar.com/posts/francis-albert-sinatra-my-way-and-all-that-jazz/</guid><description>Francis Albert Sinatra or as commonly known as Frank Sinatra is, in my humble opinion, one of the best crooners that ever lived. His songs have healed my soul when I needed it the most, guided me while dealing with my feelings, and empowered me to make bold decisions in my life. Even though we never shared a time frame in our existence, I have to thank him for always being there for me.</description></item><item><title>A Night at the Opera: Così Fan Tutte</title><link>https://albertazemar.com/posts/a-night-at-the-opera-cosi-fan-tutte/</link><pubDate>Fri, 22 Apr 2022 01:05:40 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://albertazemar.com/posts/a-night-at-the-opera-cosi-fan-tutte/</guid><description>I&amp;rsquo;ve just arrived home from the Gran Teatre del Liceu. Tonight I witnessed one of the most magical opera nights of my life. The play was Cosi Fan Tutte, the third collaboration between Wolfgang Amadeus Mozart and Lorenzo da Ponte. Let me tell you that I&amp;rsquo;m still in shock. The amount of joy, laughter, and overall positive feelings that I&amp;rsquo;ve experienced tonight was unprecedented.
As per usual, I arrived 20 minutes before the start.</description></item><item><title>New Feature: Gallery</title><link>https://albertazemar.com/posts/new-feature-gallery/</link><pubDate>Wed, 20 Apr 2022 19:46:21 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://albertazemar.com/posts/new-feature-gallery/</guid><description>I&amp;rsquo;m quitting Instagram. I&amp;rsquo;m sick and tired of wasting my precious time scrolling. I always thought of myself as someone above all of those issues that are often pointed out about social media. But the situation has reached a point where I can&amp;rsquo;t take it anymore. The amount of hours that I&amp;rsquo;m pouring on the platform is increasing exponentially, so I quit.
I haven&amp;rsquo;t talked about it yet, but I&amp;rsquo;m into analog photography.</description></item><item><title>Planes Busses and Opera</title><link>https://albertazemar.com/posts/planes-busses-and-opera/</link><pubDate>Sat, 16 Apr 2022 11:23:48 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://albertazemar.com/posts/planes-busses-and-opera/</guid><description>Planes, busses, and opera Well, I&amp;rsquo;ve just landed at Bilbao Airport. I&amp;rsquo;m having a bit of a headache, probably caused by sleep deprivation or caffeine withdrawal. So ordering a double expresso seemed to be the obvious solution. Little did I know that I would be greeted with an overpriced coffee soup worthy to be served at Central Perk.
To reach my final destination, Zarautz, I&amp;rsquo;m taking a bus that leaves in 30 minutes.</description></item><item><title>Catalan Chess League 2022 Round 3: My First Classical Game</title><link>https://albertazemar.com/posts/catalan-chess-league-round-3-my-first-classical-game/</link><pubDate>Thu, 14 Apr 2022 19:01:36 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://albertazemar.com/posts/catalan-chess-league-round-3-my-first-classical-game/</guid><description>Introduction Well after I started taking chess lessons, I received an unexpected e-mail: I was selected to play in the Catalan chess league next Sunday. Being a Tuesday, I was at the office. And having started in a new company merely two weeks ago, I was not in shape. I had neglected chess training for most of that month. In all that mess, I forgot to uncheck my name from the available player&amp;rsquo;s list for that game.</description></item><item><title>Hello World, Again!</title><link>https://albertazemar.com/posts/hello-world-again/</link><pubDate>Mon, 11 Apr 2022 23:03:41 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://albertazemar.com/posts/hello-world-again/</guid><description>So my blog is back. I started this project in March 2020 during the lockdown as a fun way to learn a bit about Django, python&amp;rsquo;s web app framework, and AWS (Amazon Web Services). I had some prior experience using Django from my first internship at NTT. If you are someone who has an interest in diving into this framework, I would strongly recommend CoreyMS 1 video series on YouTube about it.</description></item><item><title>About Me 👨‍💻</title><link>https://albertazemar.com/about/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://albertazemar.com/about/</guid><description>About</description></item><item><title>Gallery</title><link>https://albertazemar.com/gallery/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://albertazemar.com/gallery/</guid><description>Gallery</description></item></channel></rss>