<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"><channel><title>Shenanigans on Albert Azemars' Blog</title><link>https://albertazemar.com/categories/shenanigans/</link><description>Recent content in Shenanigans on Albert Azemars' Blog</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 09 Aug 2022 00:14:16 +0200</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://albertazemar.com/categories/shenanigans/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Magic the Gathering, Dreams and Nostalgia</title><link>https://albertazemar.com/posts/mtg-dreams-and-nostalgia/</link><pubDate>Tue, 09 Aug 2022 00:14:16 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://albertazemar.com/posts/mtg-dreams-and-nostalgia/</guid><description>People that have known me since I was an undergrad know that from 2015 to 2019, I was an active Magic The Gathering (MTG) player. For the uninitiated, MTG is a trading card game invented by Richard Garfield in the 90s. Each player must build a deck with a minimum of 60 cards with a maximum of 4 copies of the same card. These can be chosen from a pool of thousands.</description></item><item><title>Planes Busses and Opera</title><link>https://albertazemar.com/posts/planes-busses-and-opera/</link><pubDate>Sat, 16 Apr 2022 11:23:48 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://albertazemar.com/posts/planes-busses-and-opera/</guid><description>Planes, busses, and opera Well, I&amp;rsquo;ve just landed at Bilbao Airport. I&amp;rsquo;m having a bit of a headache, probably caused by sleep deprivation or caffeine withdrawal. So ordering a double expresso seemed to be the obvious solution. Little did I know that I would be greeted with an overpriced coffee soup worthy to be served at Central Perk.
To reach my final destination, Zarautz, I&amp;rsquo;m taking a bus that leaves in 30 minutes.</description></item><item><title>Hello World, Again!</title><link>https://albertazemar.com/posts/hello-world-again/</link><pubDate>Mon, 11 Apr 2022 23:03:41 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://albertazemar.com/posts/hello-world-again/</guid><description>So my blog is back. I started this project in March 2020 during the lockdown as a fun way to learn a bit about Django, python&amp;rsquo;s web app framework, and AWS (Amazon Web Services). I had some prior experience using Django from my first internship at NTT. If you are someone who has an interest in diving into this framework, I would strongly recommend CoreyMS 1 video series on YouTube about it.</description></item></channel></rss>